nationwide.com 2006-04-19

# privacy | Nationwide.com

At Nationwide, we respect your right to privacy, and we promise to treat your information responsibly. It’s as simple as that. Here’s how:

**Confidentiality and security**

We use physical and technical safeguards to protect your information. We limit access to your information to those who need it to do their jobs. Our business partners are bound by law to use your information only for our purposes. They may not share it or use it in any other way. We comply with all data security laws.

  **Collecting your personal information**

The information we collect from you depends on the products you buy.  We collect information from your application, business transactions with us, and consumer reports.  We use this information to sell you products, service your products, and market products to you.

**Sharing your personal information**

We do not sell your information to anyone.  We share your information with our sister companies and business partners to sell and service your products.  We have joint-marketing agreements with our business partners, who may use your information to market other products.  We may share the following types of information:

  * Name, Address, Social Security Number
  * Assets and income
  * Property address and value
  * Account information
  * Policy information
  * Credit report, motor vehicle report, medical report or employment report
  * Family member information

**Information sharing and opt out**

We may share your information with other Nationwide Companies to cross-market products that might interest you. When we have joint-marketing agreements with our business partners, we may share your information with them as well.

You can ask use not to share your information with other Nationwide Companies, our business partners, or both for marketing purposes.  Please call us toll free at 1- 866-280-1809 to opt out of this sharing.

If you have already opted out, you don’t need to opt out again.

Vermont Customers:  We won’t share your information with Nationwide Companies or our business partners for marketing purposes without your consent.

**Using your medical information**

We sometimes collect medical information for a product or service that you’re interested in buying or to pay a claim.  We may share your medical information if required or permitted by law.  But, we don’t use or share your medical information for marketing, unless you give us your permission.

**Internet Policies**

Nationwide collects and uses information from our Web sites to learn how visitors use our site and to help our customers service their policies online.  This section explains how we use the information we collect form our Web site.  Also, Nationwide contracts with business partners who help develop our Web sites. They may keep the information you provide.  If we change our privacy policy, we’ll post the changes right here. This way you can always check on what information we collect, how we use it, and when we might disclose it. 

**Collecting information**

We collect your information when you:

  * Request information from one of Nationwide's Web sites
  * Use online tools and calculators
  * Apply online for products
  * Subscribe to online services
  * Complete an online form
  * Conduct transactions online
  * Apply for a job online

**Using information**

Nationwide or our business partners use this information for:  

  * Edits and feedback
  * Marketing and promotions
  * Analysis of user behavior
  * Product development
  * Content improvement
  * Informing advertisers how many visitors have seen or clicked on their advertisements
  * Customize Web site content and layout

_**Visitor Data**_

  * We collect aggregate and specific information when you visit our site.  We log IP addresses and domain names, browser, time, and referral data. We also collect information when you fill out surveys and forms. We use this information to improve our site.
  * We collect your personal information when you visit the pages of our Web site that require you to logon using an ID and password.

_**Use of "Cookies"**_

We store a cookie on your computer when you visit our site.

A cookie is a tiny piece of information that is required to create and keep a secure session. Our cookies let you request information and do business online. Our cookies do not have confidential or personal information.  They won’t track you after you leave our site.

Some of our advertising partners may put a cookie on your computer, and these cookies may track you.  

For information, on how to opt out of these cookies, please read "Use of Clear GIFs" below.

_**Use of Clear GIFs (Graphic Interchange Format)**_

A clear GIF is a 1 by 1 pixel file placed on our Web pages. We use GIFs to track visitors and learn how they use our Web site.  We collect this information to improve our Web site. The information we collect and share through cookies and Clear GIF technology is anonymous and not personally identifiable. That means your name, address, telephone number, or e-mail address are not included.

In addition, TM Advertising uses Clear GIFs to help manage our online advertising. These Clear GIFs are provided by TM Advertising's ad management partner, DoubleClick. These files enable DoubleClick to recognize a unique cookie on your Web browser placed by TM Advertising, or by another advertiser that works with DoubleClick.

This helps us to learn which advertisements bring users to our Web site. Again, the information that DoubleClick collects and shares through cookies and Clear GIFs is anonymous and not personally identifiable.  So there’s no name, address, telephone number, or e-mail address.

For more information about DoubleClick, including information about how to opt out of these technologies, go to http://www.doubleclick.com/us/about_doubleclick/privacy/.

_**E-mail**_

Nationwide keeps the e-mail you send to us. If you agree to receive e-mail messages from us, we’ll keep the information you give us to send e-mail of specific interest to you. If you choose to send us e-mail, we keep your e-mail, your e-mail address, and our reply. Please be careful about the information you give us in e-mail. As with any public Web site, this communication may not be secure.

_**Web Links**_

It‘s important to note that other companies or organizations may have links on our pages  and we’re not responsible for the collection, use, or security of information by the companies or organizations outside of the Nationwide family of companies. Please read the privacy policy of Web sites linked from Nationwide Web sites.

**Questions**

If you have any questions about our privacy policy, please contact us immediately. We’ll give you a copy of your personal information that we control and can reasonably retrieve.

To access your information:

  1. Tell use all policy numbers you want to access.
  2. Sign your request and have your signature notarized. This helps us ensure the identity of the person requesting the information.

While we don’t charge a fee for providing you with a copy of this information now, we reserve the right to charge a small fee in the future. You may request that we correct your personal information in our files. Please note that we  don’t control information provided by third parties. So, you’ll need to contact the third party directly to correct any information from them. Sometimes we obtain your consumer or credit report. If so, you may request the credit-reporting agency's name and address. You may ask the agency to give you a copy of your report.

**Please send privacy inquiries to:**

Nationwide Insurance  
Attention Customer Relations - Privacy  
One Nationwide Plaza, 1-5-28  
Columbus , Ohio 43215

When you write to us, please include:

  * Your name
  * Address
  * Policy number

Your agent name and number.

You can contact your agent to change information that we control, such as your address. Or, you may contact one of our  Nationwide Service Centers for help.

This privacy statement describes our privacy practices for both current and former customers. 

Thanks for choosing Nationwide.

This privacy statement is made on behalf of Nationwide Mutual Insurance Company and its affiliates and subsidiaries, which includes the companies that offer auto, home, property, life insurance, banking services, and investments. This includes the following companies:

Nationwide Mutual Insurance Co.

Nationwide Mutual Fire Insurance Co.

Nationwide Property and Casualty Insurance Co.

Nationwide General Insurance Co.

Nationwide Insurance Company of America

Nationwide Affinity Insurance Company of America

Nationwide Insurance Company of Florida

Nationwide Lloyds

Colonial County Mutual Insurance Co.

Nationwide Assurance Co.

Nationwide Securities, Inc.

**TRUSTe Privacy Program**

Nationwide is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. TRUSTe is an independent, non-profit organization whose mission is to enable individuals and organizations to establish trusting relationships based on respect for personal identity and information by promoting the use of fair information practices. This privacy statement covers the nationwide.com Web site.

Because we want to show you our commitment to your privacy, we have agreed to disclose our information practices. We also agree to have TRUSTe review our privacy practices for compliance.

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, contact Nationwide Customer Relations at 1-800-882-2822 ext. 96985, first. Then, if you  don’t receive a response from your inquiry or the inquiry is not addressed to your satisfaction, then contact TRUSTe through the TRUSTe Watchdog Dispute Resolution Process. TRUSTe will serve as a liaison to resolve your concerns with the Web site.

_This privacy statement was updated on December 2, 2005._
